{"tossups": [{"question": "A novel from this genre sees Montoni take Emily away to his residence, which she later escapes with the help of Du Pont to reunite with Valancourt. Jerome recognizes his son Theodore from a mark below his shoulder in a novel from this genre. In that novel, a prophecy that results in the death of Conrad from crushing by a giant (*) helmet scares Manfred into trying to marry Isabella. In addition to that Ann Radcliffe novel, this genre includes a novel in which Renfield lets the title character into an asylum, allowing him to attack Mina. Jonathan Harker travels to the title character\u2019s castle in Transylvania in that novel. For 10 points, name this genre exemplified by Horace Walpole\u2019s The Castle of Otranto and Bram Stoker\u2019s Dracula.", "answer": "Gothic fiction [prompt on horror]"}, {"question": "In one novel titled for this condition, a man shouts \u201cYou are losing your book!\u201d to another character after writing the number 1848 on a sheet of paper. The protagonist of that novel asks to spend a night in a prison cell and fails to sell his essay on Correggio. Near the end of a story titled for this condition, the protagonist whispers \u201cForgive me, everybody\" for retaining it. That protagonist is usually watched by butchers and is irritated when they play cards, and he is eventually replaced by a (*) panther. An unnamed narrator meets Ylajali in a Knut Hamsun novel titled for this condition, while in another story about this condition, the title character is limited to 40 days embracing it. For 10 points, name this condition that titles a Franz Kafka story about a namesake \u201cartist\u201d who chooses not to eat.", "answer": "hunger [accept alternate translations like \u201cstarving\u201d or \u201cfasting\u201d; accept Sult; accept \u201cA Hunger Artist\u201d or \u201cEin Hungerk\u00fcnstler\u201d]"}, {"question": "In one short story by this author, a man named Tonie receives a silver watch from Claire after going out on a sailboat. In another story by this author, Bobinot buys canned shrimps for his wife, who still loves a man she met at Assumption and cheats with during the title phenomenon. This author wrote about Calixta in that story, (*) \u201cThe Storm,\u201d as well as a story in which Armand kicks out the title character over what he assumes is her mixed race heritage, unaware that he himself is part black. In another story by this author, a woman shouts \u201cFree! Free! Free!\u201d upon hearing of her husband\u2019s death in a railroad disaster but dies of a heart attack when he returns alive. For 10 points, name this author of \u201cA Story of an Hour\u201d and \u201cDesiree\u2019s Baby,\" who also wrote about Edna Pontellier in The Awakening.", "answer": "Kate Chopin [accept Katherine O'Flaherty]", "subcategory": "Short Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "The title character of one of this author\u2019s novels befriends the shop owner Beharry. Ramlogan sells five taxis to the protagonist of that novel, who wins an election on the slogan \u201cA vote for Ganesh is a vote for God.\u201d In another novel by this author, the protagonist hides after losing a cow, causing his father to drown while searching for him. This author wrote about a character who can cure illnesses with his hands and wrote a novel in which a pundit predicts that the protagonist will \u201ceat up his (*) parents\u201d after being born with an extra finger. Besides writing The Mystic Masseur, this man wrote about a character who does not like his wife Sharma or her family, the Tulsis. The journalist Mohun finally acquires the title structure on Sikkim Street in that novel by this author. For 10 points, name this Trinidadian author of A House for Mr. Biswas.", "answer": "V. S. Naipaul [or Sir Vidiadhar Surajprasad Naipaul]", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This poem mentions \u201cdirges due in sad array\u201d before a depiction of \u201cyon aged thorn.\u201d This poem, which imagines a man who might have woken to the \u201cliving lyre,\u201d pictures \u201cChill Penury\u201d repressing individuals\u2019 \u201cnoble rage\u201d and freezing their souls\u2019 \u201cgenial current.\u201d The speaker of this poem imagines \u201csome hoary-headed swain\u201d might one day mention seeing him \u201cbrushing with hasty steps the dews away.\u201d This poem concludes with an epitaph to a (*) \u201cyouth to Fortune and to Fame unknown.\u201d The speaker of this poem wonders if \u201csome heart pregnant with celestial fire\u201d is laid nearby before imagining a \u201cmute inglorious Milton.\u201d This poem, which depicts \u201csome Cromwell guiltless of his country\u2019s blood,\u201d begins, \u201cThe curfew tolls the knell of parting day.\u201d A place \u201cfar from the madding crowd\u201d is mentioned in, for 10 points, what poem by Thomas Gray?", "answer": "\u201cElegy Written In A Country Churchyard\u201d", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "A character in this play declares \u201cthe Great Work begins\u201d after crashing through the roof of another character\u2019s apartment. A speech asking \u201care we doomed?\u201d and \u201ccan we change?\u201d is delivered by a Bolshevik in this play. According to a character in this play, God left Heaven after the 1906 San Francisco earthquake. Mr. Lies guides one character in this play through (*) Antarctica; that character, Harper, is addicted to Valium. The drag queen nurse Belize asks another character to recite the Kaddish and steals a stash of AZT. The ghost of Ethel Rosenberg appears to Roy Cohn in this play, in which Louis Ironson deserts Prior Walter. For 10 points, name this play about the AIDS epidemic by Tony Kushner.", "answer": "Angels in America", "subcategory": "Drama", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This character is described by another as a \"creature,\" although \"Old dogs have more dignity.\" This character used to be able to dance \"the jig, the fandango and even the hornpipe.\" This character is given the commands Up, Back, Stop, and Turn to prevent him from falling asleep while he carries a bag full of sand. This character ponders the existence of (*) God \"with white beard\u2026 outside time without extension\" and the \"great cold\" Earth. This character\u2019s monologue is riddled with meaningless words like \u201cacacacacademy\u201d and \u201cquaquaquaqua\u201d and trails off when Vladimir removes his hat. For 10 points, what usually-silent character gives a long, incoherent monologue after being commanded to \u201cThink!\u201d by his master Pozzo in Samuel Beckett\u2019s Waiting for Godot?", "answer": "Lucky", "subcategory": "Drama", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "A character of this ethnicity named Victor travels to pick up his father\u2019s ashes in one story. One character of this ethnicity throws a geometry textbook at his teacher Mr. P after he sees Agnes Adams\u2019 signature in it. That character with this ethnicity helps lead his basketball team to a victory against his former school Wellpinit. Another member of this ethnicity named Thomas (*) Build-the-Fire creates the band Coyote Springs. Chess and Checkers Warm Water are two members of this ethnicity from Montana. A novel centering on this ethnic group sees Junior leave \u201cthe rez\u201d to attend Reardan High School. For 10 points, name this ethnic group which includes author Sherman Alexie and characters in his Reservation Blues and The Absolutely True Diary of a Part-Time Indian.", "answer": "Native Americans [accept American Indians before the end; accept Spokane Indians]", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "The protagonist of one novel by this author sees a poster asking for a French speaker who could perform secretarial duties for a woman living at \u201cDonceles 815.\u201d In another novel by this author, the title \u201cIndiana General\u201d attempts to trick another character by shooting a pig that is consuming a dead body. Lorenzo is sent away to Cocuya land in one novel by this author, upsetting the protagonist\u2019s wife (*) Catalina. Felipe falls in love with the title green-eyed Aura in a novel by this author, while another sees the title character lie about the location of his will to his daughter Teresa and her mother. The protagonist of one novel by this author is forced by Tomas Arroyo to sleep with Harriet Winslow; that character is later revealed to be the author Ambrose Bierce. For 10 points, name this author of The Old Gringo and The Death of Artemio Cruz.", "answer": "Carlos Fuentes", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "In one poem by this author, the speaker states that the title objects are \u201cliable to melt in snow\u201d before asking \u201cAre your fingers long enough to play / Old keys that are but echoes?\u201d Another poem by this writer says \u201cCompass, quadrant, sextant, contrive / No further tides\u201d before claiming \u201cmonody shall wake the mariner.\u201d A poem by this writer begins \u201cWe make our meek adjustments\u201d and mentions finding a \u201cfamished kitten on the step.\u201d This author of \u201cMy Grandmother\u2019s Love Letters\u201d depicted the \u201cbell rope that gathers God at dawn\u201d in \u201cThe (*) Broken Tower.\u201d This poet of \u201cChaplinesque\u201d claimed \u201cthis fabulous shadow only the sea keeps\u201d in one poem, and incorporated \u201cPowhatan\u2019s Daughter\u201d into an epic inspired by a Brooklyn landmark. For 10 points, name this American poet of \u201cAt Melville\u2019s Tomb\u201d and The Bridge.", "answer": "Hart Crane", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "A character in this novel is unable to play the harpsichord due to her love for the protagonist, who kisses that character\u2019s muff 100 times. Two characters in this novel argue about whether human nature is inherently virtuous or full of sin, and one of those characters is later found sleeping with the protagonist\u2019s first love interest. The protagonist of this novel breaks his arm saving someone from (*) falling off of a horse. That protagonist runs away to London where he duels Mr Fitzpatrick for the hand of Mrs. Waters. The gamekeeper Black George receives charity from this novel\u2019s protagonist, who is found as a baby swaddled between the linens of Squire Allworthy\u2019s bed. Sophia Western leaves Blifil for the title \u201cfoundling\u201d in, for 10 points, what Henry Fielding novel?", "answer": "The History of Tom Jones: A Foundling", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "In a story from this collection, a landowner tells the narrator of how he shed no tear for his wife\u2019s death until he witnessed a fly crawling on her eye. An old woman uses the last of her money to pay a priest to deliver her funeral rites in a story from this collection titled \u201cDeath.\u201d Foggy recounts the story of two foresters in this collection\u2019s section \u201cRaspberry Water.\" The narrator falls ill and his attending physician tells him of his former love for the dying girl (*) Alexandra in this collection\u2019s story \u201cDistrict Doctor.\" The narrator observes the contrast between the two title peasants in the first story in this collection, and occasionally travels with Yermolay. \u201cKhor and Kalinych\u201d is a story from, for 10 points, what short story collection that takes place over a hunting trip, written by Ivan Turgenev?", "answer": "A Sportsman\u2019s Sketches", "subcategory": "Short Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "The speaker of a poem from this collection declares that \u201c[he] made a second marriage in [his] house\u201d and \u201cdivorced old barren reason from [his] bed.\u201d Another poem in this collection asks the reader to \u201cFear not lest Existence closing your account\u201d; that poem inspired the pen-name of Hector Hugh Munro. The opening of this collection implores the reader to (*) \u201cWake! For the Sun,\u201d and another poem in this collection debates \u201cwho is the potter, and pray, who is the pot?\u201d An Agatha Christie novel takes its name from a poem in this collection which begins \u201cThe Moving finger writes, and having writ, / Moves on.\u201d The speaker asks for \u201cA Jug of Wine, a Loaf of bread\u2014and Thou\u201d in, for 10 points, what poetry collection famously translated by Edward FitzGerald and attributed to Omar Khayyam?", "answer": "The Rubaiyat of Omar Khayyam", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "Monica Fairview wrote a fanfiction-turned-novel about this character\u2019s cousin called \u201cThe Other [this character].\u201d This character says that poetry, as \u201cthe food of love,\u201d can only strengthen strong relationships after another character discusses how poetry drives away suitors. This character is described by saying his money \u201ccan\u2019t save him from having a most forbidding, disagreeable countenance.\u201d This character foils his sister (*) Georgiana\u2019s marriage to his worst enemy and later pays that enemy to marry Lydia. That estate is run by Mrs. Reynolds and is in Pemberley. This character is first introduced at a ball where he introduces Jane to his friend Mr. Bingley. For 10 points, name this man who eventually marries Elizabeth Bennet in Jane Austen\u2019s Pride and Prejudice.", "answer": "Mr. Fitzwilliam Darcy", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "One poem by this author depicts a leaf falling in loneliness, and another of his poems describes the \u201cgoat footed Balloonman\u201d who \u201cwhistles / far / and / wee.\u201d One of this author\u2019s poems echoes back to phrases like \u201ci am never without it\u201d as well as the title phrase. This writer wrote one poem describing its title character who \u201cride[s] a watersmooth-silver stallion.\u201d The title character of another poem by this writer is described by saying \u201cunless statistics lie he was more (*) brave than me:more blond than you,\u201d and his most famous poem describes \u201csummer autumn winter spring\u201d and \u201csun moon stars rain.\u201d For 10 points, name this author of \u201cI Sing of Olaf Big and Glad\u201d and \u201canyone lived in a pretty how town\u201d, well known for his lack of capitalization and unique punctuation.", "answer": "ee cummings (or Edward Estlin Cummings)", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "Irnerio surprises the protagonist of this novel by saying he learned how to not read before sending the protagonist to the department of Bothno-Ugaric languages. In this novel, the Chief of Police introduces himself to another character by saying \u201cZeno of Elea'' and tells that character to board a train. The protagonist of this novel supposedly read the book Leaning from the steep slope by Ukko Ahti, a fact revealed to him by (*) Cimmerian expert Professor Uzzi-Tuzii. Ermes Marana created havoc in the publishing world after switching around book titles in this novel. The protagonist of this novel meets Ludmilla in a bookstore after being unable to finish the title book. For 10 points, name this Italo Calvino novel that centers on \u201cyou, the reader.\u201d", "answer": "If on a winter\u2019s night a traveler [or Se una notte d'inverno un viaggiatore]", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "One of these characters tells a narrative centering around a sailor\u2019s wife with \u201cchestnuts in her lap\u201d who \u201cmunch\u2019d and munch\u2019d and munch\u2019d.\u201d These characters listen to an angry remark \u201cHave I not reason, beldams as you are?\u201d before whispering \u201ccome let\u2019s make haste.\u201d In their most famous scene, one of these characters remarks about the time where the \u201chedge pig\u201d whines while another shortly replies, \u201cHarpier cries.\u201d One of these characters remarks \u201cI come Graymalkin\u201d after agreeing on a meeting (*) \u201cwhen the hurly burly\u2019s done.\u201d One of these characters remarks \u201csomething wicked this way comes\u201d in response to one character\u2019s arrival, and earlier concludes that a character will be denied future kingship to the descendants of Banquo. For 10 points, name this trio of mysterious women who devise Macbeth\u2019s prophecy.", "answer": "the three witches from Macbeth [or the Weird Sisters]", "subcategory": "Drama", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "In the prologue to this book, the main character pees her pants while trying to recite a church poem. The main character of this book destroys a piece of china to get fired from a job as a maid and is afraid that she is a lesbian, leading her to become pregnant with her son, Guy. That main character gets a scholarship to the California Labor School while living in Oakland, and becomes San Francisco\u2019s first (*) African-American female streetcar conductor at age 16. This book\u2019s main character\u2019s mother Vivian marries Mr. Freeman, who rapes his step-daughter and is murdered after being acquitted in St. Louis. Bailey and his sister live with Momma in Stamps, Arkansas at the start of, for 10 points, what autobiography by Maya Angelou?", "answer": "I Know Why the Caged Bird Sings", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "The final section of one poem by this author is the origin of a phrase meaning \u201clove conquers all.\u201d The protagonist of one poem by this author is warned that he will someday eat his own tables out of hunger; that curse is innocuously resolved when he eats a meal on a base of bread. One poem by this man includes a section where the shepherd Corydon attempts to woo Alexis. The birth of a child in that poem by this author is hailed as the \u201cgreat increase of (*) Jove,\u201d which Christians linked to Jesus Christ. The protagonist of one poem by this author descends to the underworld with a golden bough on the advice of the Cumaean Sibyl. In that poem by this author, Dido commits suicide on a funeral pyre after the protagonist leaves Carthage to found the Roman race. For 10 points, name this Roman poet of the Eclogues and the Aeneid.", "answer": "Publius Vergilius Maro [accept Virgil]", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "The protagonist of a novel set in this country takes pictures of her students with and without robes. The Guardians of the Revolution search the house of the protagonist of one novel set in this country. The protagonist of one novel set in this country teaches The Great Gatsby and Pride and Prejudice to her private class. After a Scud missile kills the protagonist\u2019s Jewish neighbors, the protagonist of one novel set in this country leaves for (*) French school in Austria. One memoir set in this country relates oppression of the government towards the title book by Vladimir Nabokov. The first chapter of a novel set in this country is titled \u201cThe Veil\u201d and discusses the beginning of this country\u2019s Islamic Revolution. For 10 points, name this country, the setting of Marjane Satrapi\u2019s Persepolis and Azar Nafisi\u2019s Reading Lolita in Tehran.", "answer": "Islamic Republic of Iran [or Jomhuri-ye Eslami-ye Iran; or Persia]"}], "bonuses": []}